JESSICA CLAIRE

resumesample@example

(555) 432-1000,

Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

•

• :

A

SUMMARY

Veteran Air Force Intelligence Officer experienced in analyzing threats and managing projects such as security, threat mitigation, and training. Excellent communication skills built from presenting critical information to high level officers and government civilians on a daily basis. Experience working with international partners for combine regional security initiatives. Trained and experienced strategic and tactical planner for joint and combined military contingency exercises. Health and fitness professional of eight years and strong motivator of groups to improve health and wellness through self-regulation principles.

HIGHLIGHTS

- Top Secret/ Secrete
 Compartmentalized Inform
 clearance
- · Project management
- Leadership
- Creative and innovative prosolving
- Professional certification in fitness
- CPR/AED certified
- Customer service

EDUCATION

University of Texas El Paso El Paso, Texas • 2015 – ‑

M.S.: Kinesiology - GPA: GPA 3.85; Teacher's assistant f undergraduate and graduate c

Air Force Squadron Officer School

, • 2013 – –

Professional Career Training: Military Leadership - GPA: Via e-correspondence-Squadron level leadership and tactical/ operational planning

Air Force Intelligence Officer School Goodfellow AFB, TX • 2010 – –

Professional Career Training: USAF Intelligence - GPA: Radar theory, treat evaluation, presentation skills, & analytical skills

University of Arizona Tucson, AZ • 2008 –

B.S.: Health Science-Physiology, Chemistry -GPA: Minor in Chemistry; GPA 3.44; Dean's List

CERTIFICATIONS

Personal Trainer Certification: American Council of Exercise A 2013-2017 CPR/AED: American Red Cross

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Air Force Commendation Medal Bachelor's Degree GPA 3.44; Dean's List Masters Degree GPA 3.85

EXPERIENCE

Pae Government Services Inc - Personal Trainer, Group Fitness Instructor Kansas City, MO, • • 01/2015 - Current

- Created group fitness routines and implemented high impact cardiovascular endurance, strength, core and balance classes. Maintained high attendance and promoted additional class involvement. Expanded certifications to include Insanity Live and Silver Sneakers.
- Run an online health and fitness accountability group. Inspired health changes and exercise promotion to a 10 member group. Provided self-regulation and behavioral adaptations for health and fitness.

Geo Group Inc. - Intelligence Planner
Milledgeville, GA, • • 05/2012 - 09/2013

- Identified intelligence requirements and threats to assets for operations and contingencies in the central and South America; experienced briefing executives.
- Provided analysis for courses of action selection and positioning of forces in conjunction with representatives from Peru, Brazil, Colombia and joint forces in multiple combatant command operations.
- Personally evaluated three Honduran intelligence units; identified areas for improvement and essential milestones in the regional mission of countering transnational organized crime.
- Developed syllabus and instruction materials for mobile training team for a Peruvian intelligence unit, and provided threat awareness training materials to Colombian air and ground forces.
- Reviewed joint publications and orders for accuracy and clarity and made significant contributions to joint publications for changes in content. Drafted intelligence plans for combatant command exercises.

Geo Group Inc. - Intelligence Officer Robstown, TX, • • 10/2011 - 04/2012

- Leader of four man team, analyzed threats, prepared aircrew, drafted and reviewed over 2000 mission reports. Coordinated critical materials with six international partners for high value targets.
- Upheld security protocols for sensitive compartmentalized intelligence facility.
 Regained access to four critical systems. Surveyed aircrew credentials monthly to ensure qualification for access to platforms mission and capability. Prepared four members with 12 hours of training to gain mission readiness.
- Directed the production of 14 advanced aircraft academic briefings to maintain mission readiness for 94 pilots. Developed method to report significant events in the threat area and improved threat awareness.

23rd Operations Support Squadron - Intelligence Officer City, STATE, • • 10/2009 - 04/2012

- Mentored eight intelligence personnel; informed leadership of threats to assets at deployed locations. Selected to brief high level officers and Congressional Representative on the capabilities of the unit.
- Reorganized manuals and checklists in preparation for operating inspection.
 Created continuity for new intelligence support position on Commanders Action Team.
- Oversaw career development training of four airmen to receive on time or early mission qualification. Over 240 hours of sophisticated training including radar theory, history, tactics, and presentation skills.
- Authored and presented over 50 threat briefings in support of combat search and rescue exercises, weapons instructor course, and daily pilot threat proficiency training
- Managed informational, physical, and personnel security for 200 personnel.
 Updated security operating instructions. Ensured all personnel met background investigation requirements and mission qualification.
- Physical fitness leader for 20 personnel. Organized and led challenging fitness program that produced a 100% pass rate for the flight and increased scores by 25%. Personnel remained mission ready.
- Showed ability to organize, manage, and adapt by successfully organizing the Air Force Assistance Fund annual donation for the installation of over 10,000 personnel, raising \$68,000 in a two month period.
- Recovered 27,000 pages of historical documents covering over 50 years of 23
 Fighter Group heritage and submitted historical material to the Air Force
 Historical Review Agency.

University Of Arizona Recreation Center - Personal Trainer & Group Fitness Instructor

City, STATE, • • 03/2007 - 01/2009

Created specialized wellness programs for clients. Included challenging cases of extreme obesity, debilitating illness (scoliosis, epilepsy), mental illness (depression and anxiety), and injury.

SKILLS

Microsoft Office (Power-point), Presentation Skills, Social Media Branding, Inspection and Quality Assurance, Health and Wellness Programing, Personal Training, Drafting and Editing Publications, Scientific Methods, Customer Service, & Organization